MARCELO ARAÚJO

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

marcelomaidden@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with over ten years of experience in the public sector. Self-motivated and fast learner proficient with Linux and Windows Operating Systems. Looking to develop software that can help peoples' lives to be easier.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, MySQL, Python, Django

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote Sep, 2020 – Present

Full Stack Web Developer

Slack bot to retrieve Google Calendar — Slack bot APP that retrieves all Calendars and upcoming events when they are mentioned on Slack conversations.

Built with: Ruby

News Week Website's clone - Responsive website's design based on News Week website.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, and Twitter Bootstrap framework)

MICROVERSE

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) Oct, 2020 – Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

INSTITUTO FEDERAL DE EDUCAÇÃO, CIÊNCIA E TECNOLOGIA DE SÃO PAULO

Campos do Jordão, Brazil

I.T Technician I.T. Support in software development and network infrastructure

Oct. 2010 - Present

- Created a system to automate students' grades' calculations, attendance scores, decreasing by 90% the time teachers spent calculating it by hand.
- Redesigned network infrastructure using VLANs, allowing different networks to share resources and each network to have its own rules.
- Virtualized Operating Systems using Citrix XenServer, which helped in a better distribution of Server Resources.
- Created Docker containers to provide services faster, decreasing considerably the amount of time spent to start new network services.
- Participated in Active Directory Samba 4's implementation, which was important to centralize user credentials and information that could be used in different systems.
- Implemented GLPI to create support tickets providing teams to open support calls, which reduced in 70% time spent to solve the company's team's issues.
- Implemented Fusion Inventory attached to GLPI to provide Network Devices' inventory, which helped make reports from network
 equipment and best divide resources.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

Sep, 2020 - Present

- Spent 338+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

INSTITUTO FEDERAL DE EDUCAÇÃO, CIÊNCIA E TECNOLOGIA DE SÃO PAULO Degree, System Analysis and Development

Jan, 2012 - Dec, 2014